One of the most popular tools for making webpack
使 webpack 便于使用的最受欢迎的工具之一
convenient to use is called the webpack-dev-server.
是 webpack-dev-server
I think it's one of the big reasons that webpack is popular,
我认为这是 webpack 流行的主要原因之一
and I know that it's one of the things that makes
该工具使 webpack 开发起来非常快速
The webpack-dev-server allows you to create a server for development mode
webpack-dev-server 允许创建只针对开发模式的服务器
only and it allows you to run files and run updates immediately.
使你可以立即运行文件并即时更新
It's what allows Create React App to have that hot reloading feature which is so nice.
这也是让 Create React App 拥有如此出色的热重载特性的原因
So first let's talk about what the webpack-dev-server is doing.
首先 了解一下 webpack-dev-server 能做什么
Right out of the box,
开箱即用
the webpack provides the ability to watch certain files.
webpack 提供了监视 (watch) 特定文件的能力
When we say watch, it just means that webpack is going to watch
这里的 watch 是说 webpack 要监视
the entire dependency tree to see when you make changes to those files.
整个依赖关系树 来查看你何时对这些文件进行了更改
So if you're in your text editor and you save a file,
如果你在文本编辑器中保存了文件
webpack can recognize that a change just happened on that file.
webpack 可以侦测出该文件刚刚发生了更改
You can run this directly by adding a dash dash watch into the command.
你可以直接在命令中添加 --watch 来运行
When we add this dash dash watch into the file,
当我们将 --watch 添加到命令参数中时
you can see that when we run the command,
你会看到运行命令时
something different will happen.
会有一些不同的行为
A webpack never finishes running.
webpack 不会停止运行
You can see here that it's just waiting for new files,
可以在这里看到它在等待新文件
or it's waiting for something to happen.
或等待什么事情发生
In fact, it's watching all of our files to see if something happens.
实际上 它正在监视我们所有的文件 看是否有改动
So if we go back to our index.js file,
如果我们回到 index.js 文件
and we add just another alert to see that something happened.
简单添加了另一个 alert 看看接下来会发生什么
Here, you can watch that webpack is noticing that something happened,
这里 可以看到 webpack 注意到有事情发生
and it's reasserting the compilation of all these files.
重新运行了对所有文件的编译
That's really cool, but it's still it's not quite as ergonomic
确实很酷 但这仍然没有预期的
as some people would hope for and it can't just restart your browser.
那样人性化 不能重启你的浏览器
The big thing is that if I'm working with this and I have my local host setup
难点在于 如果我在开发该文件 设置了本地主机
even if I save a file over here and webpack knows to rebuild my distribution folder,
即使在此处保存文件 并且 webpack 知道要重新构建分发文件夹
I still have to refresh my browser to see the change.
仍然要刷新浏览器才能看到更改
So if we don't want to have to refresh our browser to see the change,
所以 如果不想刷新浏览器就看到更改
webpack has the webpack-dev-server,
webpack 提供了 webpack-dev-server
and that will allow the hot reloading feature that so many people love.
它支持很受欢迎的热重载功能
To install the webpack-dev-server,
要安装 webpack-dev-server
I'm going to stop the server,
我得先停止服务器
and we're going to install the webpack-dev-server.
再安装 webpack-dev-server
Once that's finished loading,
加载完成后
we can just add the webpack-dev-server to our command in our package.json file.
只需要将 webpack-dev-server 添加到 package.json 文件的命令中
So to edit the build-dev script,
编辑 build-dev 脚本
we're now just going to replace it with this,
现在要将其替换为这个脚本
and the webpack-dev-server here tells webpack that
这里的 webpack-dev-server 告诉 webpack
we're going to use the dev server to run this webpack dev file,
我们将使用开发服务器来运行 webpack 开发配置文件
and we're going to open it automatically every time we run it.
每次运行时我们都要自动打开浏览器
So now, if we ran the npm build-dev script,
所以现在 如果运行 npm build-dev 脚本
we should see it open a new browser window for us with our app running.
可以看到它打开了一个新的浏览器窗口来运行应用
As you can see, we get our eye exist alerts from the index.js file, all of them.
如你所见 有多个来自 index.js 文件的 alert
You can see that, none of our styles are showing up,
你会发现 我们的样式一个都没有出现
but that's actually expected because we haven't
但这实际上是与预期相符的 因为我们还没有
set up any of our styles to be imported through webpack.
设置通过 webpack 导入任何样式
The only things that are showing up here are
这里唯一出现的是
the index HTML file and the JavaScript files that we've imported.
index.html 文件和我们导入的 JavaScript 文件
So it looks about like we would expect it to.
所以是符合预期的